前情提要
Previously on
Those About to Die...
这就是奴隶不接受命运的下场
That's what happens to slaves
when they don't accept their fate.
新买的奴隶，会被带到哪里去？
Newly bought slaves,
where would they be taken?
你需要钱。
You need money.
- 很多钱。- 你在玩一个危险的游戏。
- Lots of money.
- You play a dangerous game here.
你觉得天蝎座会离开我们去别的阵营吗
Do you think Scorpus is
leaving us for another faction?
他在策划什么事。
He's up to something.
这个是处女
This one is a virgin.
- 三千塞斯特斯。- 妈妈！
- Three thousand sesterces.
- Mother!
五百
Five hundred.
你想利用这个女儿作为中间人来监视你的敌人。
You seek to use this daughter as a
go-between to spy on your enemy.
我来当你的中间人。
I will be your go between.
提图斯你将成为皇帝
Titus, you will be Emperor.
维苏威火山的黄色火山灰
The trick with the yellow
ash of Mount Vesuvius
并没有使用太多。
is not using too much.
太多了，治愈比诅咒更糟糕。
Too much, and the cure
is worse than a curse.
多少才算太多？
How much is too much?
这就是艺术
That's the art of it.
众神就在里面。
The Gods reside within.
他们住在哪里？
Where do they stay there?
你应该改变你中间两匹马的位置。
You should change the positions
of your middle two horses.
你的大马在左中锋，
You have your big
horse left center,
他应该在中间
and he should be right center.
我做得很好。
I've done all right.
当然，我...说说而已
Of course, I'm... just saying.
你开车吗，安德里亚？
Do you drive, Andria?
两匹马大部分。
Two horse gigs mostly.
但我开过四辆，
But I've driven fours,
我曾经开过一辆六号车
and I once drove a six.
人印象深刻.
Impressive.
我知道我还有很多要学。
I know I have a lot to learn.
我是个乡下人，
I'm a provincial boy,
就像你曾经一样
just as you once were.
但你学会了，我也会。
But you learned, so will I.
有一天我也会在马克西姆斯马戏团开车
And, one day, I, too, will
drive in Circus Maximus,
喜欢你你
like you.
没人能像我一样开车。
Nobody drives like me.
我们回罗马吧。
Let's get back to Rome.
埃利亚，斑点的那个刚死了
Elia, the mottled one just died.
伦诺和费罗克斯一样的母马和公马，年轻一个赛季。
Lenno. The same mare and
sire as Ferox, a season younger.
他从来没有像Ferox那么快，但他有一颗多么好的心。
He was never as fast as
Ferox, but what a heart he had.
他会一直跑直到爆炸。
He would have
run until it exploded.
跟我说说这个叫Tenax的人
Tell me of this man Tenax.
比某些人好，比某些人差。
Better than some,
worse than others.
他在马克西姆斯马戏团做生意赌博。
He does business
betting at Circus Maximus.
买，卖，做我看不见的事。
Buying, selling, doing
things I don't see.
我不会说的，即使我看到他们。
I would not speak
of, even if saw I them.
带她去马苏斯领事馆，确保她能联系上她女儿.
Get her to the House of Consul Marsus,
and make sure she contacts her daughter.
我需要玛索斯和安东尼娅的消息。
I need ears on
Marsus and Antonia.
求你了
Please.
稍等求你了
One moment. Please.
你完好无损吗？
Are you intact?
靠近一点
Come closer.
好.德鲁斯利亚会教你该学的东西
Good. Drusilla here will train
you in what you need to know.
说话
Speak.
你不能从一次触摸中知道她的童贞。
You could not know her
virginity from a single touch.
不是我的触摸证实了这一点。
It wasn't my touch
that confirmed it.
是她的眼泪。
It was her tears.
- 德鲁斯利亚- 克劳迪娅
- Drusilla.
- Claudia.
这是你们家新来的女孩的母亲。
This is the mother of
the new girl in your house.
去厨房
Go, to the kitchen.
茱拉
Jula.
你怎么会在这里？我们该怎么办？
How can you be here?
What are we to do?
安静点
Quiet.
我们时间不多了
We don't have much time.
有些事你得去做
There are things you need to do.
仔细听好了。
Now listen carefully.
我儿子也在罗马，
My son is in Rome as well,
被认为是角斗士
taken to be a gladiator.
他会在哪里？
Where would he be?
竞技场。来了
The Ludus Magnus. Come.
这太疯狂了
This is madness.
我不会参与的
I will have no part of this.
- 去吧- - 你说什么？
- Go then.
- What?
等等他说这会害死他们。
Wait. He said it
could kill them.
我们还能做什么
I mean, what else can we do?
在马厩里放乌鸦，铃铛吓跑鬼魂？
Put crows in their stalls,
bells to scare away the spirits?
加夫罗斯？
Gavros?
如果我们什么都不做，他们会死的。
They'll die, if we do nothing.
有了这个，或许他们还有机会。
With this, perhaps
they have a chance.
让我来吧
Let me do it.
放松放松放松轻轻是的
Easy, easy, easy,
easy. Gently. Yes.
号我早料到了。
No. I saw that coming.
用网
Use the net.
在我落网之前别想三叉戟了。
Forget the trident
until I'm snared.
号
No.
你得骗我。
You have to trick me.
人比动物聪明。
Men are smarter than animals.
现在你学乖了
Now you're learning.
反面.进攻方防守
Reverse. Attackers, defend.
好.
Good.
走！走！
Move! Move!
把我搞糊涂了。
Confuse me.
如果我动一下，你就知道了。你会知道的。
If I move, you will
learn. You will know.
如果我还活着，你就得猜。
If I'm still, you have to guess.
水
Water.
是谁教你打猎的？
Who taught you the
hunting of animals?
动物？
Animals?
当我还是个孩子的时候，
When I was a boy,
我父亲会笑着说
my father would
say that and laugh.
“向猎物学习，而不是向我学习。"
"Learn from the
prey, not from me."
但我都是跟他学的。
But I learn it all from him.
他来自努比亚，
He was from Nubia,
黑法老的土地
the land of the Black Pharaohs,
从远古时代起我们就和国王一起打猎
where we have hunted with
kings, since the dawn of time.
当我会爬的时候，他教我抓老鼠和鼹鼠。
When I could crawl, he taught
me to catch mice and moles.
当我还能走路的时候，到处都是蜥蜴、野兔和狐狸。
When I could walk, it was
lizards and hares and foxes.
当我可以和他一起跑的时候，我们把所有有价值的猎物都带走了。
When I could run alongside
him, we took all the worthy prey.
他怎么死的？
How did he die?
罗马人杀了他。
Romans killed him.
为什么？为什么？
Why?
因为他们是罗马人。
Because they are Romans.
这就是他们所说的四帝之年。
It was what they called the
Year of The Four Emperors.
罗马人打罗马人
Romans fighting Romans.
我父亲为错误的罗马人而战。
My father fought for
the wrong Roman.
维斯帕先赢了，他向失败者复仇。
Vespasian won and took his
vengeance against the losers.
第一个罗马人是双胞胎。
The first of the
Romans were twins.
罗穆卢斯和雷穆斯被母亲抛弃，任其自生自灭。
Romulus and Remus, abandoned
by their mother, left to die.
一只母狼发现了它们，给它们喂奶，并把它们养大为狼
A she-wolf found them, suckled
them and raised them as wolves
在帕拉蒂尼山上的一个山洞里
in a cave on a
hill called Palatine.
维斯帕先和他的儿子们的宫殿就在那里。
Where the palace of Vespasian
and his sons now stands.
狗，即使是像拉科尼亚人和狐狸这样的野蛮人，也只在饥饿的时候才杀人。
Dogs, even savage ones like Laconians
and vulpines only kill when hungry.
甚至土狼。
Even hyenas.
它们是很讨厌的生物，它们只在饥饿的时候杀人。
The nasty creatures they
are, they only kill when hungry.
狼是不同的。
Wolfs are different.
狼以杀人为乐。
Wolves kill for pleasure.
就像罗马人一样。
Like the Romans.
那你呢
And what of you?
从战场上带走的？
Taken from a battlefield?
不，在城垛上，我们的女人和孩子在我们后面。
No, on a battlement, with our
women and children behind us.
在北方，有耻辱和投降。
In the north, there is
shame and surrender.
但这是让我们的家人活下去的唯一办法。
But it was the only way
to keep our families alive.
我妻子和儿子都在罗马。
My wife and son
are here in Rome.
从第一个小时到第十二个小时，她为他们编织。
From the first to the 12th
hour, she weaves for them.
我儿子七岁了。
My son is seven.
他花了两年时间在地毯上，
He has spent the last
two years hooking a rug,
有钱的罗马人会踩在上面
that will be walked on by
the feet of rich Romans.
我可以在Kalends上看到他们，有时，每个月的Nones。
I get to see them on the Kalends and,
sometimes, the Nones of each month.
所以你梦想得到木剑。
And so you dream of
gaining the Wooden Sword.
也许有一天
Maybe one day.
科隆，弗拉玛，过来。
Colon, Flamma, come here.
科隆，两天后你将在马克西姆斯竞技场和弗拉玛决斗
Colon, you will fight Flamma
in two days in Circus Maximus
在战车比赛之前
before the chariot races.
维果，
Viggo,
你和夸梅是科隆的武器兵
you and Kwame will be
Colon's weapons men.
一定要把他的尸体卖个好价钱。
Make sure you get a
good price for his body.
有办法进去吗？
Is there a way to enter?
容易.做一个肌肉发达，有男子气概的奴隶，随时准备为罗马的荣耀而被屠杀。
Easy. Be a well-muscled, manly slave ready
to be butchered for the glory of Rome.
走开
Be off.
你不是罗马人。
You are not Roman.
你是叙利亚人
You're Syrian.
求你了
Please.
我儿子在里面。
My son is in there.
嘿，等等！
Hey, wait!
夸梅
Kwame!
朱拉和奥拉呢？
What of Jula and Aura?
朱拉是马苏斯领事家的奴隶
Jula is a slave in the
house of Consul Marsus,
而奥拉的主人是一个叫特奈克斯的罪犯
and Aura, she is owned by a
criminal, a man called Tenax.
他们还好吗？
Are they well?
他们还活着
They're alive.
- 小心- 别生气。
- Watch out.
- Hold your anger.
别再惹麻烦了
Don't make more trouble.
我会把你从这里救出来。
I'll free you from here.
- 我不这么认为. - 我会的我保证
- I don't believe so.
- I will. I promise.
你得走了
You must go.
你在干什麽？你说什么？
What are you doing? Huh?
你为什么这么恨你哥哥？
Why do you hate
your brother so much?
我不知道我爱你是因为你的愚蠢还是因为你的愚蠢。
I don't know whether I love you in
spite of your stupidity or because of it.
这不是个愚蠢的问题
It's not a stupid question.
为什么要当皇帝？
Why aspire to be Emperor?
没有它，你仍然可以拥有曾经可能想要的一切。
Without it, you can still have
everything once could possibly want.
我对泰特斯是个威胁。
I am a danger to Titus.
所以他才说服我父亲不让我当军事指挥官。
That's why he convinced my
father to deny me military command.
所以我才被管得这么紧，
It's why I've been kept
on such a tight leash,
乞求足够的钱来生活，
begging for enough
money to live,
即使在哄骗了参议院之后，
even after cajoling the Senate,
争取他们支持我父亲的事业
winning them over
to my father's cause,
给了他一把教长椅
giving him the curule chair.
我变成什么了？
I've been made what?
Aedile Ludi？
Aedile Ludi?
- 地方官卢迪是一个受人尊敬的职位。- 我是一个表演者。
- Aedile Ludi is a position of respect.
- I'm a showman.
我的哥哥，军人，是受人尊敬的。
My brother, the
soldier, is respected.
当我还是个孩子的时候，他折磨我。
When I was a boy,
he tormented me.
这使他觉得好笑。
It amused him.
他会在他的士兵朋友面前打我让我哭。
He'd strike me in front of his
soldier friends and make me cry.
训练场上，
On the training field,
他会给我一把剑，激我向他进攻
he would put a sword in my
hand and dare me to attack him.
但当我这样做的时候，他会一次又一次地打我。
But when I did, he would
strike me again and again.
笑
Laughing.
- 在他们面前羞辱我。- 他很年轻。
- Humiliating me before all of them.
- He was young.
他太残忍了！
He was cruel!
最终，这种折磨变成了宽容。
Eventually, that torment
turned to tolerance.
但当我父亲去世时，这种宽容就会变成恐惧。
But when my father dies,
that tolerance will become fear.
他会杀了我
And he will kill me.
除非我已经解决了你
And unless I've
disposed of you already,
他会把你和我一起沿着
he'll kill you along with me.
如果我没有野心，我就死了。
If I'm not ambitious, I'm dead.
不好意思
I'm sorry.
我想现在没有理由留下来了。
No reason to stay
now, I suppose.
埃利亚
Elia!
来了
Come.
快点.快点.快点.
Hurry. Hurry. Hurry.
快点，快点。
Quickly, quickly.
费洛斯费罗克斯
Ferox. Ferox!
好孩子
Good boy.
非洲人
African.
我需要工作。
I need work.
还有工资
And a wage.
我在马克西姆斯马戏团有个赌酒屋。
I have a betting tavern
at the Circus Maximus.
你们两个可以在那里工作。
You two could work there.
付钱？
Pay?
- 我们走着瞧- 马！
- We'll see about that.
- The horses!
死而复生。
Back from the dead.
我欠海王星一个牺牲。
I owe Neptune a sacrifice.
- 他们很弱。- 但越来越强壮。
- They are weak.
- But getting stronger.
有多强？我们明天比赛。
How much stronger?
We race tomorrow.
比我们买的马还强壮。
Stronger than the
nags we bought.
你给我找了第二个司机吗
Did you find me a second driver?
没有人像你和我一样愚蠢。
No one else is as
foolish as you and I.
没人想把拇指
No one wants to
shove their thumb
从传统的角度来看，并加入第五个派系。
in the eye of tradition
and join a fifth faction.
- 两匹马？- 四个。
- Two horse gigs?
- And fours.
你被录取了
You're in.
来了
Come.
装了不会更容易的。
Pretend. It won't go easier.
我有没有告诉过你我对你这个丈夫的评价有多高？
Have I ever told you how highly
I think of you as a husband?
不，我不记得了。你有过这样的想法吗？
No, not that I can remember.
Have you ever had such a thought?
比你想象的还要多。
More times than you might think.
天蝎座告诉我们他要永远离开蓝军
So Scorpus told us he's
leaving the Blues for good.
- 嗯. - 但他根本不知道是我
- Hmm.
- But he didn't even know it was me
下令毒死他的马
who ordered his horses poisoned.
- - 你说什么？那是你吗？- 当然了
- What? That was you?
- Of course.
你重新获得我们派系的控制权，我来保护它。
You regain controlling interest
of our faction, and I protect it.
我突然想起来我为什么嫁给你了。
I suddenly remember
why I married you.
- 我为什么要用这种... - 尊重？
- To what do I owe this expression of...
- Respect?
- 爱呢？- 爱也是。
- And love?
- Love as well.
嗯嗯
Mm-hmm.
天蝎座是个好司机，不会让他开卡车来对付我们的。
Scorpus is too good a driver to
let him take the truck against us.
你介意我安排他的死吗
Do you mind if I
arrange his death?
不我没有
No, I don't.
来了
Come.
这是什么？
What's this?
礼物
A gift.
她完好无损。
She's intact.
这是你以前用的香水
It's the same scent
you used to wear.
我以为你会喜欢的。
I thought you might enjoy that.
走了走！
Go. Go!
他在哪里？
Where is he?
茱拉来了
Jula's here.
来了
Come.
有人看见你离开吗？
Did anyone see you leave?
号好.你有什么要给我的？
No. Good. What
do you have for me?
- 他们说要杀人- 是谁？
- They said they're gonna kill someone.
- Who?
- 可能是带S的东西。- 天蝎座？
- It could be something with an S.
- Scorpus?
是的天蝎座
Yes. Scorpus.
把她带回来，确保没人看见她。
Get her back, make
sure no one sees her.
噢，茱拉。
Oh, Jula.
你好吗？他们对你好吗？
How are you? Do
they treat you well?
我很好。
I'm fine.
来了快
Come. Quickly.
我想看看跑道是什么样的。
I wanted to see what
the running surface is like.
是的，他们在转弯时换了粗粒沙子。
Yeah, they switched the
coarser grain sand on the turns.
我们得向左急拉才能守住防线。
We have to pull hard
left to hold the line.
人们认为我是个有天赋的酒鬼傻瓜
People think I'm a
gifted, drunken fool.
我赢是因为福图纳在我母亲子宫里摸过我。
That I win because Fortuna
touched me in my mother's womb.
我妈妈是个妓女。福图纳从来没来看过我们。
My mother was a whore.
Fortuna never came to visit us.
我赢了，因为，和你一样，
I win, because, like you,
在比赛的前一天晚上，我来到椭圆球场测试沙子。
the night before a race, I come
to the oval and I test the sand.
明天，我就死了。
Tomorrow, I die.
是的
Yes.
弗拉玛杀死高卢人时
When Flamma killed the Gauls,
我帮忙把它们剩下的东西搬到动物围栏里。
I helped carry what was left
of them to the animal pens.
没人来取他们的尸体
No one came for their bodies,
阿提克斯的肉卖了20塞斯特斯
and Atticus got 20
sesterces for the meat.
我是个战士，战士的儿子，
I'm a warrior, son of a warrior,
最后一个辛布里人
the last of the Cimbri people.
我可不想最后变成老虎屎。
And I do not wish to end
up as shit from a tiger.
我希望像我父亲和祖父那样结束，
I wish to end as my
father and grandfather did,
就像从战士的柴堆上升起的烟雾，升到星星上。
as smoke rising from a warrior's
pyre, ascending to the stars.
我来负责你的火葬。
I will see to your pyre.
谢谢
Thank you.
我也不想最后变成老虎屎。
I don't wanna end up
as shit from a tiger either.
如果我还活着，我会看着办的。
If I'm still alive,
I'll see to it.
那你呢
What of you?
谁来照顾你的柴堆？
Who will attend to your pyre?
我喜欢老虎。
I like tigers.
我不介意最后变成老虎屎。
I wouldn't mind ending
up as shit from a tiger.
- 天蝎座。- 女士们
- Scorpus.
- Ladies.
- 你说什么？
What?
你说什么？
Huh?
他们在干什么？
What are they doing?
- 是天蝎座！- 是天蝎座！
- It's Scorpus!
他们在攻击天蝎座
They're attacking Scorpus.
出去
Out.
你在嘲笑我。
You astonish me.
你在说什么啊？
What are you talking about?
整个罗马都知道，天蝎座死了。
All of Rome knows,
Scorpus is dead.
一场毫无线索的街头犯罪。
A street crime with
no hint of who did it.
干得好
Well done.
不是我
It wasn't me.
- - 你说什么？- 我想一大早就杀了他，
- What?
- I wanted to kill him in the early morning,
所以没时间找人替代他
so there will be no
time to replace him.
哦，好吧，那对我们更好。
Oh, well, all the better for us.
我们是清白的。
Our hands are clean.
另外，新派系的马
Add to that, that the
new faction's horses
几乎跑不动还被无名小卒驾驶
can barely run and they're
being driven by nobodies.
一对西班牙新郎。
A pair of Spanish grooms.
有一件事我们要处理。
There's one thing we
need to take care of.
我们需要一个新司机。
We need a new driver.
你有什么想法吗
Do you have any thoughts?
我知道
I do.
我们是来清点帝国账目的
We are here to tally
the Imperial Accounts.
一些光。
Some light.
也许一些隐私？
Maybe some privacy?
你们每一个人五个这个
Each of you. Five of these.
为什么要搞阴谋？它是你的了
Why the intrigue? It's yours.
好吧...
Well...
在某种意义上。
in a sense.
站住
Halt.
卢修斯
Lucius.
分散赌注。每人不超过一万塞斯特斯。
Spread the bets. No more
than 10,000 sesterces each.
一切都会失去。
All to lose.
殿下，恕我直言，这说不通
Your Highness, with
respect, that makes no sense.
你不可能赢所有人。
You can't win betting
against everyone.
照我说的做
Do as I say.
所有这些，悄悄下注，
All of this, quiet bets,
绿色、红色、蓝色和白色将输。
that Green, Red, Blue
and White shall lose.
我觉得胜算很大。
I expect excellent odds.
爱马仕。
Hermes.
我的王后
My Queen.
你给我带来了什么，金匠？
What have you
brought me, Goldsmith?
帝国国库的标志。
The mark of the
Imperial Treasury.
我们为图密善重铸了40根金条。
We've recast 40
gold bars for Domitian.
向你唯一的，孤独的上帝祈祷？
Praying to your one, lonely God?
- 是的- 你问他要什么？
- Yes.
- What do you ask him for?
原谅
Forgiveness.
有些事情只有上帝才能原谅。
There are some things
only God can forgive.
说说看
Try me.
我为我的家人祈祷
I pray for my family.
家庭是危险的。
Families are dangerous.
他们能比你在马戏团的退休人员更彻底地诱捕你。
They can ensnare you more completely
than your retiarius in the Circus.
哦，你是说我的家人。
Oh, so you mean my family.
图密善是个男孩，而我是个战士。
Well, Domitian is a
boy, and I am a soldier.
你以为你的剑能保护你吗
You think your
sword will protect you?
是的，还有禁卫军。
That and those of the
Praetorian Guards, yes.
我的祖父，大希律王，总是说，
My grandfather, Herod
the Great, always said,
“用剑杀死蝎子可不容易。"
"It is not easy to kill a
scorpion with a sword."
你弟弟的野心越来越大了。
Your brother grows
more open in his ambition.
这是什么？
What's this?
看起来是一根有皇家印章的金条
Appears to be a gold bar
with an Imperial Stamp.
- 你从哪弄来的？- 不，问题是，你从哪弄来的？
- Where did you get it?
- No, the question is, where did you get it?
- 不是我有，是你。- 别耍我！
- Well, I'm not the one who has it, you are.
- Do not toy with me!
你从帝国金库里拿的
You took it from the
Imperial Treasury.
我没做过这种事。
I did no such thing.
不管是谁告诉你的，他们都在撒谎。
And whoever told
you I did, they're lying.
他们为什么要这么做？
Why would they do that?
离间我们对很多人都有好处。
There are many who would benefit
from driving a wedge between us.
如果你愿意，我会去查的。
If you wish, I'll look into it.
我已经这么做了。
I've already done so.
我已经下令对财政部进行会计核算。
I've ordered an
accounting of the Treasury.
原谅我，但那是我的领域。
Well, forgive me,
but that is my domain.
不会太久的
Not for long.
他会杀了你
He will kill you.
他可能会。
He may.
你打算怎么办？
What are you going to do?
财政部很大，清点库存需要时间。
The Treasury is large,
an inventory will take time.
今天我赢了，我会把借的钱还回去，把我的金库填满。
When I win today, I'll return
what I borrowed and fill my coffers.
希望足够买几个禁卫军。
Hopefully enough to
buy some Praetorians.
- 他们很贵的，禁卫军。- 如果你没赢呢？
- They're expensive, Praetorians.
- And if you don't win?
我想我会死的。
Then I expect I'll die.
你可以和我一起死
You can die with me.
你疯了吗？我不能为布鲁开车
Are you mad? I
can't drive for Blue.
白色让我富有。
White has made me rich.
再说，雷托会杀了我的。
And besides, Leto would kill me.
他可以试试。
He may try.
我们会保护你的
We will protect you.
雷托现在付你多少钱？
How much does Leto pay you now?
罗马都知道。
All Rome knows.
每个赛季600，000塞斯特斯，相当于您向天蝎座支付的费用。
600,000 sesterces a season,
equal to what you pay Scorpus.
- 我们会把它翻三倍。- 安东尼娅...
- We will triple that.
- Antonia...
一季一百六十万？
1,600,000 a season?
我想是一季180万。
I believe it's
1,800,000 a season.
就现在，今天，今天的比赛？
Right now, today,
for today's race?
现在，否则免谈。
Right now, or no deal.
我要开英西塔图斯。
I get to drive Incitatus.
当然了
Of course.
我给你开车。
I'll drive for you.
但你得阻止雷托杀了我。
But you have to keep
Leto from killing me.
我们会尽力的。
We'll try our very best.
父亲你还没准备好
Father, you're not ready.
- 父亲？- 你说什么？
- Father?
- Huh?
我弄错了
I made a mistake.
我犯了一个可怕的错误。
I made a terrible mistake.
- 一个错误？- 是啊
- A mistake?
- Yeah.
我们的步兵太远了。
Our infantry is too far away.
我应该保留六个步兵团作为后备。
I should have kept six
cohorts of infantry in reserve.
- 你应该休息。- 你说什么？
- You should rest.
- Huh?
- 你应该休息。- 是谁？
- You should rest.
- Who?
- 来了- 喂。
- Come.
- Oi.
谢谢
Thank you.
我知道我可以永远依靠你..
I know I can
always rely on you...
泰特斯
Titus.
是的，父亲。
Yes, Father.
做该做的事。
Do what needs to be done.
你应该更信任我，兄弟。
You should trust
me more, brother.
我最想要的就是这个
There's nothing I'd like more.
我会等财政部的人告诉我是否可以。
I'll wait for the count of the
Treasury to tell me if I can.
到时候我会接受你的道歉
Well, I'll accept your
apology when the time comes.
父亲身体不舒服
Father is, uh, indisposed.
他今天不会来了。
He won't be joining us today.
我发誓我要把他们全杀了
By the Gods, I'll kill them all!
玛索斯安东尼娅卡托尼娅
Marsus, Antonia, Caltonia!
最重要的是，Xenon！
Most of all, Xenon!
兰图勒斯的新战车在哪里？
Where are the new special
chariots from Lentullus?
他说他们被偷了。
He claims that they were stolen.
- 偷来的？- 是的
- Stolen?
- Yes.
我该怎么办呢？
What should I do?
带后备司机来！
Bring up a reserve driver!
使用旧战车！
And use the old chariots!
- 天啊！- 你们三个，准备战车。
- Dear Gods!
- You three, prepare this chariot.
你，备马。
You, prepare the horses.
来吧！
Come on!
罗马的市民们！
Citizens of Rome!
我来介绍今天的第一场比赛。
I present you, our
first bout of today.
伟大的火焰杀手中的杀手
The Great Flamma,
killer of killers,
阿奎索斯，将战斗
colossus, will do battle
与强大的科隆！
with the mighty Colon!
我们即将死去，
We who are about to die,
向您致敬。
salute you.
角斗士，准备！
Gladiators, ready!
开火！
Engage!
你，一个军人，觉得血很恶心？
You, a soldier, finding
blood distasteful?
不是讨厌。
Not distasteful.
浪费。
Wasteful.
无论是摆脱，保卫还是扩张我们的边境，
Whether it is shed, defending
or expanding our frontier,
这就是血液发挥作用的地方
that's where blood
serves a purpose.
它在这里也有作用，兄弟。
It serves a purpose
here as well, brother.
火焰！火焰！火焰！
Flamma! Flamma! Flamma!
弗拉玛！火焰！火焰！
快点.来了
Hurry. Come.
- 多愁善感。- 这是什么？
- Sentimental.
- What is this?
Caltonia.
哦对不起我以为你知道。
Oh, I'm sorry. I
thought you knew.
我们又买了500股。
We've acquired
another 500 shares.
我认为这使我们成为主要股东。
I believe that makes us
the leading shareholders.
我相信你会觉得这些座位很舒服。
I'm sure you'll find those
seats quite comfortable.
哦，顺便说一句，虽然我们都哀悼
Oh, and by the way,
although we all mourn
我们挚爱的天蝎座的逝去
the passing of our
beloved Scorpus,
我们决定雇佣氙
we've taken it upon
ourselves to hire Xenon.
他今天会为我们开车。
He'll be driving for us today.
马苏斯你怎么敢
Marsus, how dare you?
氙是我的司机。
Xenon is my driver.
那你应该给你的人更高的薪水参议员好好享受比赛吧。
Then you should pay your people
better, Senator. Enjoy the race.
以阿塔加蒂斯的名义，我在哪里？
By the name of
Atargatis, where am I?
哦妈的我在流血
Oh, shit. I'm bleeding.
我们得让它看起来像真实的。
We had to make it look real.
是你吗
That was you?
你这个肮脏的罗马人。
You filthy Roman.
所以你想杀了伟大的天蝎座
So, you tried to kill
the great Scorpus, huh?
不当然没有
No, of course not.
安东尼娅下令杀了你
Antonia ordered your death.
- - 你说什么？- 我是想保证你的安全。
- What?
- I'm trying to keep you safe.
如果你死了，没人会想杀你。
If you're dead, no
one will try to kill you.
安东尼娅？
Antonia?
不，她爱我。
No, she loves me.
她有一种特殊的表达方式。
She has a very particular
way of showing it.
还有一件事
And one other thing.
你的裁缝送来的。
A delivery from your tailor.
今天，只有四个派别在为胜利而战。
Today, just literally four
factions are running for victory.
有史以来第一次，我们为您呈现...
For the first time in
history, we present you...
黄金阵营！
The Gold Faction!
司机，不是别人，
With driver, none other than
伟大的天蝎座！
the great Scorpus!
我以为他死了。
I thought he was dead.
那些是我们的！
Those are ours!
他们是我们的！
They're ours!
- 天蝎座还活着？- 糟了
- Scorpus is alive?
- Worse.
看，氙是为蓝军开车。
Look, Xenon is
driving for the Blues.
天蝎座还活着！
Scorpus is alive!
三百赌天蝎座！黄金阵营。
Three hundred on
Scorpus! Gold Faction.
一个叫Tenax的平民不知怎么筹到了足够的钱
A plebeian, called Tenax
somehow raised enough money
组建一个新的派系从蓝队雇佣天蝎座
to form a new faction and hire
Scorpus away from the Blue.
就是他，在那边
That's him, over there.
作为市政官鲁迪，
As Aedile Ludi,
我想观众看到自己人上台会很高兴。
I thought it might please the crowd
to see one of their own up here.
显然，我是对的。
Apparently, I was right.
记住，不要用鞭子。
Remember, no whip.
- 只是一个笛鲷。他在哪里？- 天啊，
- Just a snapper. Where is he?
- Boy,
离开那里
get out of there.
战车！
Chariots!
准备！
Ready!
等等等等
Wait. Wait.
天蝎座。
On Scorpus.
来吧！
Come on!
啊！啊！
Yah! Yah!
我把赌注压在天蝎座身上。
I placed the bet on Scorpus.
- 来吧！来吧！- 来吧！
- Come on! Come on!
- Come on!
来吧！
Come on!
是啊是啊
Yeah. Yeah.
来吧，我们走。比赛开始了来吧我们走
Come on, let's go. The
race is on. Come on, let's go.
母亲
Mother.
啊！
Yah!
快点！快点！
Now!
我们怎么打赌？
How have we bet?
很严重。
Heavily.
最后一局！最后一局！现在就走！
Last round! Last round! Go now!
啊！
Yah!
现在就走！走！
Go now! Go!
快点。快点。快点。
Come on. Come on. Come on.
走了走了走！
Go. Go. Go!
快点。再快点。
Come on. Faster.
更多.给天蝎座更多！
More. Give Scorpus more!
坚强点，费罗。
Stay strong, Ferox.
Incitatus，保持。
Incitatus, hold.
- 等等，因西塔斯。- 你在干什麽？
- Hold, Incitatus.
- What are you doing?
啊！
Yah!
是的，我会的
Yes!
哦，谢谢！
Oh, thank you!
你不留下来颁奖吗？
You're not going to stay
and present the laurels?
号
No.
因为我要去参加帝国财政部的会计会议。
Because I have an accounting
of the Imperial Treasury to attend.
今天真不错。
Quite a day.
我只能猜测在你的领导下我们的派系接下来会发生什么。
I can only guess what's next for
our faction under your stewardship.
我一想到就不寒而栗。
I shudder to think.
该死的黄金阵营！去死吧！
Damn the Gold
Faction! Go to hell!
从来只有四个派系！
There's only ever
been four factions!
几个世纪以来都是这样！
It has been that
way for centuries!
天蝎座！那个混蛋在哪
Scorpus! Where's that bastard?
我会把你的所作所为报告给帮派老板
I'm gonna report everything
you did to the faction owners.
别惹因西塔斯。
Leave Incitatus alone.
恩，我和因西塔斯是老朋友了。
Well, me and
Incitatus are old friends.
朋友个屁
Friends, my ass.
别管他了，别再玩阴的了。
Just leave him alone
and stop playing dirty.
走了
Go.
你叫什么名字？
What was your name?
索菲亚。
Sofia.
我们应该再来一次。
We should do this again.
你不能再增加一个派系。
You can't just add
another faction.
太荒谬了！
Absolutely ridiculous!
两千塞斯特斯换我女儿奥拉的自由
Two thousand sesterces for
my daughter Aura's freedom.
这是从哪里来的？
Where did that come from?
我在这里赢的，
I won it here,
from you.
我们说好了
We agreed.
我的麻烦结束后再决定价格。
I decide the price when
my troubles are over.
据我所知，你的麻烦永远不会结束。
From what I've seen of you,
your troubles will never be over.
一千
One thousand.
你欠我的我告诉了你茱拉的秘密。
You owe me for the secrets
I shared with you from Jula.
- 一千五- 一千
- Fifteen hundred.
- One thousand.
好吧
Fine.
你自由了
You are free.
为什么是我？
Why me?
妈妈，茱拉和夸梅怎么办？
Mother, what about
Jula and Kwame?
一步一步来，女儿。
One step at a time, daughter.
Tenax！
Tenax!
有四个派系。你听到了吗？四个！
It's four factions.
You hear me? Four!
这是你们的传统。
This is your tradition.
你凭什么改变一切？
Who are you to
change everything?
伙计们，我们得关门了。
Boys, we need to close up.
- 只有四个势力！- 规则被打破了！
- There's only four factions!
- The rules were broken!
我听到了，皇帝。
I hear it, the Emperor.
你怎么这么久才来
What took you so long?
你说什么？
Huh?
我要死了
I'm dying.
会计做完后，
After the accounting is done,
派更多的军队去平息暴乱。
send more troops
to quell the riot.
是的，大人。
Yes, my lord.
都在这里，直到最后一个德纳里。
It is all here, to
the last denarii.
所以她骗了我。
So, she deceived me.
提图斯将军
General Titus.
皇帝
The Emperor.
把我举起来。
Lift me up.
是啊
Yeah.
带我到房间中间。
Take me to the
middle of the room.
- 博萨- 是的
- Bosa!
- Yes.
我的月桂。
My laurel.
罗马的皇帝
An Emperor of Rome
必须死
must die
站
standing
成为神
to become divine.
是啊
Yeah.
现在我准备好了
Now I am ready...
成为...
to become...
一个神。
a God.
A God.
你父亲
Your father.
带他上床。
Take him to the bed.